-下午好，高尔特小姐。-下午好，贾德森，我想看看…
- Good afternoon Miss Gault. - Good afternoon Judson, I'd like to see...
-你好，凯特。-你想要什么?
- Hello Kate. - What do you want?
你能告诉盖伊我想见他吗?
Will you tell Guy that I would like to see him?
-恐怕他不想见你。-我得听盖伊亲口说。
- I'm afraid he doesn't wish to see you. - I shall have to hear that from Guy himself.
哦，真的吗，凯特，你不觉得至少我应该得到一个解释吗?
Oh really Kate, don't you think at least I deserve an explanation?
很好。
Very well.
请您在这里等一下好吗?
Will you please wait here?
抱歉，那家伙不想见你。
I'm sorry, guy does not wish to see you.
我告诉过你，我得听盖伊亲口说。
I told you I have to hear that from Guy himself.
——人?——艾米丽。
- Guy? - Emily.
-艾米丽你不该来这里-所以我理解。
- Emily you, you shouldn't have come here. - So I understand.
但是盖伊，你不觉得我应该得到比一封信更多的东西吗?
But Guy, don't you think I deserve something a little more than a letter?
-看着我，告诉我你不爱我。-亲爱的，我真的很爱你。
- Look at me and tell me you don't love me. - My darling, I do love you very much.
所以我才给你写那封信因为我真的爱你。
That's why I sent you that letter because I do love you.
现在，亲爱的，请你走开，忘记你曾经见过我。
Now, darling, please go away and forget you ever met me.
我知道发生了什么，盖伊。我父亲告诉我的。
I know what happened Guy. My father told me.
不管他怎么想，他有没有告诉你原因。
Did he tell you why, despite what he thinks.
我不是逃离棺材里的东西而是逃离我内心深处的东西。
I didn't run away from what was inside that coffin but from what I knew to be inside me.
我，我不明白。
I, I don't understand.
我本想省了你的。
I'd hoped to spare you this.
如果你真的明白了，你就会明白为什么我们之间永远不可能结婚。
If you do understand, then you'll realize why there can never be a marriage between us.
跟我来。
Come with me.
-这条路通向哪里?——下面。
- Where does this lead? - Below.
-你没事吧?-是的，我想是的。
- Are you all right? - Yes I, I think so.
-你想回去吗?-不，不。
- You want to go back? - No, no.
你经常说想见见我的家人。
You've often expressed a wish to meet the rest of my family.
好吧，这些都是我的祖先，有名的和臭名昭著的……放在这里，这个词是什么?休息。
Well, here they are all my ancestors, famous and infamous... laid here to, what is the term? To rest.
从一开始，死亡就像刺客一样来到卡雷尔家…但最不幸的是我父亲。
From the beginning, death has come to the Carrells like an assassin... but the least fortunate of all is my father.
他是怎么死的?
How did he die?
就像黑暗里的一根蜡烛。
Like a single candle in a dark and airless room.
-艾米丽，我父亲…-人…-凯特，你怎么来了?-该吃药了。
- Emily, my father... - Guy... - Kate, why you here? - It's time for your medicine.
-哦，是的，我忘了，对不起，谢谢。-什么药?
- Oh yes, I'd forgotten I'm sorry, thank you. - What medicine?
鸦片酊。
Laudanum.
-伙计，这就是…-不，不是原因，是结果。
- Guy, is this the cause of... - No, not a cause, an effect.
没有它们我就睡不着。
Without them I couldn't sleep.
伙计，告诉我。
Guy, tell me.
那晚我不该和你父亲还有其他医生一起去的。
I should never have gone with your father and those other doctors that night.
我只对私人研究感兴趣。
I'm interested only in private research.
我永远不会忘记那个被他们洗劫了坟墓的可怜人。
I can never forget that poor wretch whose grave they robbed.
他瞪大的眼睛，紧握的双手……他的指甲……在徒劳无功地撬开棺材盖的过程中，他浑身是血。
His staring eyes, his clutching hands... his fingernails... broken and bloody from the vain attempt to claw away the lid of that coffin.
你看，这一切对我来说都有特殊的意义艾米丽。
You see, all this has a special meaning for me Emily.
多年来，我一直生活在被活埋的恐惧中。
For years I've lived in dread of being buried alive.
你能想象吗?
Can you possibly conceive it?
肺部难以忍受的压迫，潮湿土地上令人窒息的烟雾……棺材僵硬的拥抱，漆黑的夜……而沉默，就像汹涌的大海。
The unendurable oppression of the lungs, the stifling fumes of the damp earth... the rigid embrace of the coffin, the blackness of absolute night... and the silence, like an overwhelming sea.
然后……在黑暗中看不见，但对其他感官来说却太可怕了……-征服者蠕虫的出现。——人?
And then... invisible in the darkness but all too hideously real to the other senses... - the presence of the conqueror worm. - Guy?
-对不起。-这些都是病态的幻想。
- I'm sorry. - These are just morbid fantasies.
恐怕不是，我的每一个家庭成员都遭遇了暴力和可怕的死亡。
I'm afraid not, every member of my family has met with a violent and horrible death.
现在轮到我了。
I now wait my turn.
-你父亲是怎么死的?-晕厥，你知道那是什么吗?
- How did your father die? - Catalepsy, you know what that is?
当它来袭的时候，死者表现出死亡的迹象。
When it strikes, the victim gives every outward sign of being dead.
但他没死，他还活着。
But he's not dead, he's alive.
我父亲患病时我才13岁。医生说是心脏病发作…有个葬礼，他被封存在这个地窖里。
I was barely 13 when my father was stricken... doctor said it was a heart attack... there was a funeral and he was sealed in this vault.
那天晚上……我听见他在哭喊，一声可怜的、绝望的哭喊。
That night... I heard him crying out, a pitiful, desperate cry.
我恳求他们，我恳求他们。他还活着他还活着我说…——但是没有人会相信我。-因为那不是真的
I begged with them, I pleaded with them. He's alive, he's alive I said... - but no one would believe me. - Because it wasn't true.
这是。
It was.
-我听到了。-在你心里。
- I heard him. - In your mind.
不,凯特。
No, Kate.
这对我来说更容易接受。
It would be easier for me to accept that.
但我知道真相。上帝保佑，我知道真相。
But I know the truth. God help me, I know the truth.
这是我父亲的遗产也是我送给你的结婚礼物。
My father's inheritance and my wedding gift to you, catalepsy.
现在你知道我为什么请求你的原谅了吧。
Now you know why I asked your forgiveness.
-没什么好原谅的。-但你必须明白…我知道我爱你，我想成为你的妻子。
- There's nothing to forgive. - But you must understand... I understand that I love you and that I want to be your wife.
Gault小姐……-我哥哥病了。-那我就照顾他，让他恢复健康。
Miss Gault... - My brother is ill. - Then I shall nurse him back to health.
艾米丽……盖伊，如果你爱我，如果你真的爱我你就不会把我排除在你的生活之外。
Emily... Guy, if you love me, if you really love me you won't shut me out of your life.
你会让我和你分享的。
You'll let me share it with you.
-你想要吗?在你听到这些之后?-比以往任何时候都多。
- You want that? After what you've heard? - More than ever before.
告诉她盖伊，告诉她。
Tell her Guy, tell her.
凯特，你考虑得太周到了你总是为我着想。
Kate, you've been most considerate and you've always thought of my welfare.
这是真的。
That is true.
但有些事情，我必须自己做决定。
But in some things, I must make my own decisions.
当然
Of course.
那么我想你已经决定了吧?
Then I take it you have made your decision?
我有。
I have.
那就让责任落在你自己头上吧。
Then let it be on your own head.
你愿意娶艾米丽为你的合法妻子吗无论顺境还是逆境，无论疾病还是健康，只要你们俩还活着?
Do you Guy, take Emily to be your lawful wedded wife... for better, for worse, in sickness and in health, so long as you both shall live?
我做的事。
I do.
艾米丽，你愿意娶盖伊为你的合法丈夫吗?无论顺境还是逆境，无论疾病还是健康，只要你们俩还活着?
Do you Emily, take Guy to be your lawful wedded husband... for better, for worse, in sickness and in health, so long as you both shall live?
我做的事。
I do.
如果这里有人知道为什么这两个人不应该在一起…在神圣的婚姻中让他现在开口，否则永远保持沉默。
If there be any here who know just cause why these two should not be joined together... in holy matrimony let him speak now or forever hold his peace.
请把戒指给我。
The ring please.
跟着我说，我和这枚戒指结了婚。
Repeat after me, with this ring I thee wed.
我带着这枚戒指娶你。
With this ring I thee wed.
那我正式宣布你们结为夫妻。
Then I do pronounce you man and wife.
-香槟夫人凯瑟琳?-谢谢。
- Champagne Lady Catherine? - Thank you.
哦，是的，一个美丽的仪式。
Oh yes, a beautiful ceremony.
敬最美丽的新娘，最幸运的新郎。
A toast, to the most beautiful bride, the most fortunate groom who ever lived.
愿他们幸福终老。
May they be happy to the end of their days.
不行，伙计，不要在大家面前。
No Guy, not in front of everyone.
那么，在我完全失去控制之前，你最好去玩点什么。
Well then, you'd better go and play something before I lose control completely.
-她是不是很漂亮?——非常。
- Isn't she beautiful? - Very.
你玩得开心吗，父亲?
Are you enjoying yourself, father?
别停止演艾米丽，很可爱。
Don't stop playing Emily, it's lovely.
祝你幸福美满。
I want to wish you every happiness.
谢谢你，迈尔斯。
Thank you Miles.
我知道你要去威尼斯度蜜月。
You going to Venice for the honeymoon I understand.
那是什么?我，对不起。
What was that? I, I'm sorry.
我问你是否要去威尼斯度蜜月。
I inquired if you were going to Venice for your honeymoon.
我不习惯和人…卡雷尔。
I'm not accustomed to people... Carrell.
请原谅我。
Forgive me, please.
这家伙到底怎么了?
What the devil is the matter with the fella?
——艾米丽。-什么事，亲爱的?
- Emily. - Yes darling?
你在弹的旋律是什么?
That melody you're playing, what is it?
-是莫莉·马龙，你不喜欢吗?-不，别玩了。
- It's Molly Malone, don't you like it? - No, please stop playing.
-但这旋律很迷人。-我说了别弹了。
- But it's a charming melody. - I said please stop playing it.
对不起，我…
I'm sorry I...
-有什么我能做的吗，盖伊?-不，没什么。
- Is there anything I can do Guy? - No, nothing.
-我跟你一起去，盖伊。-不，请别烦我。
- I'll come with you Guy. - No, please leave me alone.
你们所有人，请离我远点。
All of you, leave me alone please.
盖伊，盖伊，亲爱的。
Guy, Guy darling.
-醒醒吧，他们都走了。-是的，艾米莉。
- Please wake up, they all gone now. - Yes Emily.
-你感觉好点了吗?-我想是的。
- Are you feeling better? - I think so.
怎么了，盖伊?
What's the matter Guy?
-你在下面发生了什么?-我记不清了。
- What happened to you down there? - I can't remember exactly.
-我在和你爸爸说话，然后…-然后呢?
- I was talking with your father and then... - And the then what?
音乐，关于你演奏的音乐。
The music, something about the music you were playing.
音乐是怎么回事?
What was it about the music?
这就是他那天晚上吹口哨的曲调。
It was the tune he was whistling that night.
-是谁?-有两个人。
- Who was? - There were two of them.
斯威尼和鼹鼠是他们的名字。哦，肮脏，恶心的生物。
Sweeney and Mole were their names. Oh, filthy, disgusting creatures.
是他们打开了坟墓，一直吹着那首讨厌的曲子。
They were the ones who opened the grave and all the time whistling that loathsome tune.
亲爱的，现在只有我们了。
Darling, now we're alone.
就我们两个人。
Alone, just the two of us.
在一起。
Together.
-那是什么?-我不知道。
- What was that? - I don't know.
-听起来像尖叫。-待在这里。
- Sounded like a scream. - Stay here.
-国王，老国王。-他死了。
- King, King old fellow. - He is dead.
一定是闪电。
It must've been the lightning.
-我们把他埋了。-随你便。
- We'll bury him. - As you wish.
现在让我们从雨里出去吧，盖伊。
Now let us go in out of the rain Guy.
他只是惊呆了。
Why, he was only stunned.
-我要把他埋了。——人?
- I was going to bury him. - Guy?
我要把他埋了……活着。
I was going to bury him... alive.
草图吗?在这里吗?
Sketching? Out here?
不，不是画草图，是制定计划。
No, not sketching really, making plans.
-为了房子?-你很好奇。
- For the house? - You're very inquisitive.
我现在结婚了，妻子应该很好奇。
Well, I'm married now and wives are supposed to be inquisitive.
丈夫应该是保密的。
And husbands are supposed to be secretive.
不过，我要告诉你我的一个秘密，一个严守的秘密。
However, I'll tell you one of my secrets, a very closely guarded one.
我有能力在不碰触女人的情况下亲吻她。
I possess the ability to kiss a woman without touching her.
哦，盖伊，真的吗?
Oh, Guy really.
你不相信我?我跟你赌一先令。
You don't believe me? I'll wager you a shilling.
好吧，我接受你的打赌。
All right, I'll accept your wager.
-来吧，给我看看这个奇迹。-乐意之至。
- Come on, show me this miracle. - With pleasure.
给你。
There you are.
-那你的赌注呢?-哦，我输了。
- What about your wager? - Oh, I lose the wager.
这是你的先令。
Here's your shilling.
相信我，它值更多的钱。
It was worth much more believe me.
——人?-什么事，亲爱的?
- Guy? - Yes dear?
我们的蜜月怎么样?
What about our honeymoon?
你答应过带我去威尼斯的，记得吗?
You promised you'd take me to Venice, remember?
-你在这里不开心吗?-哦，是的，当然，但是……你太靠自己了，我很担心你。
- Aren't you happy here? - Oh yes, of course but... well, you're on your own so much and I worry about you.
你必须对我有耐心。
You must be patient with me.
好吧，与此同时，我会点亮那座沉闷的老房子。
All right, in the meantime I'll brighten up that dreary old house.
在那里。
There.
-看，他们是不是很可爱?-把它们拿走。
- Look, aren't they lovely? - Take them away.
伙计，别这么坏脾气。
Guy, don't be so ill-tempered.
我无法忍受住在一个没有花的房子里。——你也不应该。-把它们扔掉。
I can't bear living in a house without flowers... - and neither should you. - Just throw them away.
我讨厌花。
I loathe flowers.
你必须保证永远不把那些难看的葬礼装饰品带到家里来。
You must promise never to bring those sickly funeral decorations into the house.
-盖伊，我只是…-你必须答应我。
- Guy, I was only... - You must promise.
好吧，我保证。
All right, I promise.
——夫人?-是的，贾德森。
- Milady? - Yes Judson.
-亚彻医生到了，夫人。-哦，请带他进来。
- Dr. Archer has arrived milady. - Oh, show him in please.
-这边走，先生-谢谢你贾德森
- This way sir. - Thank you Judson.
艾米丽。
Emily.
-亲爱的迈尔斯，你能来真是太好了。我一收到你的信息就来了。
- Miles dear, how kind of you to come. - I came directly I received your message.
-出什么事了吗?——是的。
- Is something wrong? - Yes.
-盖伊病了。-哦，听到这个我很难过。
- Guy is ill. - Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
我想是因为意大利的气候吧。-我们没去意大利。
- I suppose it's the Italian climate. - We didn't go to Italy.
但我以为……我们从结婚那天起就一直住在这房子里。
But I thought... We've been here in this house ever since the day we were married.
-我不明白。-我也不想。
- I don't understand. - Neither do I.
我只知道盖伊病了，你得帮他，迈尔斯。
All I know is that Guy is ill and you've got to help him Miles.
但是亲爱的，你父亲已经尽力了。
But my dear, surely your father has done everything that can be done.
我父亲什么也没做。
My father has done nothing.
对他来说，盖伊是一个非常健康的人，但事实并非如此……你必须做点什么来帮助他，迈尔斯。
To him, Guy is a perfectly healthy man but that isn't true... and you must do something to help him Miles.
如果你不这样做，可怕的事情就会发生。
If you don't, something terrible will happen.
他完全变了一个人。我，我都不认识他了。
He's a completely changed man. I, I don't even recognize him.
好吧，我会尽力的。
Well, I'll do whatever I can.
-你带我去见他吧?-谢谢你，迈尔斯。
- Why don't you take me to him? - Thank you Miles.
-我刚拿到我的围巾。-你的围巾?
- I just get my wrap. - Your wrap?
但是荒野上很冷。
But it's chilly on the moors.
艾米丽……-他在哪儿?——有。
Emily... - Where is he? - There.
一个月前开始建的。
Started building it a month ago.
家伙?
Guy?
——人?——是吗?
- Guy? - Yes?
-让我进去。-走开，我很忙。
- Let me in. - Go away, I'm busy.
伙计，请开门。
Guy, please open the door.
艾米丽，你不明白吗，我说我…-你好，盖伊。-你好迈尔斯，很高兴见到你。
Emily, didn't you understand me, I said I was... - Hello Guy. - Hello Miles, I'm glad to see you.
-我必须道歉，我太粗鲁了。-是的，盖伊，你很粗鲁。
- I must apologize, I was very rude. - Yes Guy, you were, very rude.
-你知道，我病得很重。-所以我理解。
- You see, I've been quite ill. - So I understand.
盖伊，我把迈尔斯带来了看看他能不能帮你。
Guy, I have brought Miles along to see if he can help you.
你很关心我，但完全没有必要，我现在自己吃。
That's very solicitous but quite unnecessary, I'm helping myself now.
-怎么了盖伊?——如何?
- How Guy? - How?
进来吧，我带你去。
Come inside, I'll show you.
就是这样，我的宏伟计划。
This is it, my grand plan.
是什么事?来点利口酒，白兰地，还是阿蒙提拉多?
What it be? Some liqueur, brandy, amontillado?
伙计，我带了…
Guy, I brought...
现在，让我们为适当的事情干杯……死。
Now, let us drink to something appropriate... to death.
不喝酒吗?真遗憾，它真的很不错。
Not drinking? What a pity, it's really quite good.
——人?-什么事，亲爱的?
- Guy? - Yes my dear?
-你想说点什么吗?——没有。
- You wish to say something? - No.
好吧，既然这样，让我告诉你我的新成员。
Well, in that case let me tell you about my latest addition.
我前天晚上就想到了。
I thought of it the night before last.
当然，我不太可能会用它，但谁知道呢，不是吗?
Of course, it's highly unlikely I shall ever use it but one never knows, does one?
允许很容易的出口，从外面完全无法通行。
Permits of easy egress and it's completely impassable from the outside.
我同意这种安排很简单，但很有效。
A simple arrangement I grant, but effective.
伙计，这太疯狂了。
Guy, this is madness.
疯狂吗?这是唯一能解决我问题的答案。
Madness? It's the only sane answer to my problem.
我会让你知道我有多生气。
I'll show you just how mad I am.
我想她告诉过你，我父亲是一名过敏者。
I suppose she's told you my father was a cataleptic.
-不，但这并不意味着…-我也有同样的苦恼。
- No, but that doesn't mean that... - I am prone to the same affliction.
很好，让我们考虑以下问题。
Very well, let us consider the following.
说什么也没说，我发作了。假设它发生在晚餐期间。
Apropos of nothing at all, I have an attack. Let us say it happens during dinner.
艾米丽让贾德森去请医生。
Emily sends Judson to fetch a doctor.
医生来了，他检查了我，宣布我死亡。当然，我还活着。
The doctor arrives, he examines me and pronounces me dead. I am, of course, alive.
你知道晕厥的本质。
You know the nature of catalepsy.
但对世界上其他人来说，我已经走了，已经去世了。
But to the rest of the world I am gone, passed on, deceased.
所以举行了葬礼，我被带到这个墓穴，放在这个棺材里。
So a funeral is held and I'm brought down here to this vault and placed in this coffin.
送葬的人都走了，门都锁上了，只剩我一个人。
The mourners have departed, the doors are both locked and I'm alone.
现在，请密切注意。
Now, pay close attention.
现在，我的手指稍微动一下就会发生这种情况。
Now, the slightest movement of my finger caused that to happen.
我现在从棺材里出来了，但我仍然只能稍微努力一下。
I am now free of the casket but I'm still capable of only slight effort.
所以…
So...
但你说，假如没有人听到钟声，离开的哀悼者就会把两扇门都锁上。
But you say, supposing no one hears the bell, the departing mourners lock both the doors.
但这真的是万无一失吗?如果门卡住了怎么办?
But is that really foolproof? What if the gate should stick?
你看到了什么?
You see?
但是，当然，几乎不可能所有这些方法都失败。
But, of course, it's barely possible that all these methods might fail.
所以…
So...
但是工具也会坏，不是吗?
But tools break too, don't they?
一位名叫诺贝尔的瑞典化学家最近发明了一种炸药。
A recent invention by a Swedish chemist named Nobel, it's called dynamite.
这是一种炸药。
It's an explosive.
但人们怎么能确定这些东西会起作用呢?
But how can one be sure the stuff will work?
当然，这是不可能的。
One can't, of course.
所以…
So...
一个人有一点吃的，喝的……每隔五分钟或十分钟左右就会响一次铃。
one has a bit of food, something to drink... every five or ten minutes or so rings the bell.
读一份期刊或一本书。
Reads a periodical or perhaps a book.
万一紧张变成……太伟大的人可以利用音乐的舒缓效果。
In the event the strain becomes... too great one can avail oneself with the soothing effects of music.
然后就等着。
And then one simply waits.
考虑得很周全，你不觉得吗?
Rather well thought out, don't you think?
但是没有一个计划是完美的。
But no plan is ever perfect.
所以现在出现了阻力，或者应该说是致命一击。
So now comes the piece de resistance or perhaps one should say the coup de grace.
-怎么了，盖伊?-怎么了?
- What is it Guy? - What is it?
一切痛苦的解药。所有问题的答案。
The cure for all suffering. The answer to all problems.
这是通往天堂或地狱的钥匙，亲爱的……或者对虚无，毒药。
The key my darling, to heaven or to hell... or to nothingness, poison.
谢谢你，贾德森。
Thank you Judson.
-茶点已经在餐厅准备好了，夫人。-谢谢。
- Tea is ready in the dining room milady. - Thank you.
-你怎么解释迈尔斯?-我现在还不知道
- How you explain it Miles? - Well, I don't just yet.
然而，我冒昧地猜测，在墓地发生的那件事……把普遍的恐惧变成了一种特定的痴迷。
However, I venture to guess that the episode at the cemetery... changed the general fear into a specific obsession.
那你不认为这是麻痹症?
Then you don't think it's catalepsy?
他以前从没发作过，对吧?是指晕厥，晕眩吗?
He's never had these attacks before, has he? Mean fainting spells, dizzy spells?
不,不。但是他的父亲……据我们所知，癫痫并不是一种遗传疾病。
No, no. But his father... To the best of our knowledge catalepsy is not an inherited affliction.
我们中的一些人有了新的想法，我、卡格雷夫和其他一些人……可能对盖伊的案子有所帮助。
And there's a new line of thought among some of us, myself, Cargrave, and a few others... that may shed some light on Guy's case.
你看到…大多数人倾向于认为身体和精神是完全不同的。两个独立的实体。
You see... most people tend to think of the body and the mind as being totally different... two separate entities.
然而，事实上……它们实际上是相连的。
Whereas, in point of fact... they're actually linked.
没有糖。你明白我的意思吗?
No sugar. Do you follow me?
是的，我想是的。
Yes, I think so.
你看，身体上……这家伙现在可能完全正常了。
You see, physically... Guy may be perfectly sound now.
然而，这种日夜折磨着他的持续恐惧……实际上可能会导致昏睡…-现在不存在这样的条件。-我明白了。
However, this constant fear that gnaws at him night and day... may actually bring about a condition of catalepsy... - where no such condition exists now. - I see.
那么，我们能做些什么呢?
Well, what can be done?
我不确定。
I am not sure.
我一点也不确定。
I'm not sure at all.
然而，我知道盖伊的脑子就像一桶火药……最小的东西也可能点燃导火索，最无辜的死亡提醒…尸体，坟墓，任何东西。
However, I do know this that Guy's mind is like a keg of gunpowder... and the smallest thing might set the fuse, the most innocent reminder of death... corpses, graves, anything at all.
这是你必须记住的第一件事，明白吗?
That's the first thing you must remember, you understand?
是的，是的，我明白。
Yes, yes I understand.
哦，迈尔斯，我希望你能来和我们住在一起。
Oh Miles, I wish you could come and stay with us.
我只是在想。楼下的实验室。
Well, I was just thinking. The laboratory downstairs.
怎么了?
What about it?
你可能知道盖伊让我用它是为了进一步研究。
Well, you may know that Guy offered me the use of it in order to further my researches.
如果我接受他的提议，我可能会经常来这里。
If I accepted his offer, I might be able to come here from time to time.
迈尔斯，那真是太好了。谢谢，非常感谢。
Oh Miles, that would be absolutely wonderful. Thank you, thank you very much.
好了，我现在得走了，但我会回来的。
Well, I must go now but I'll be back.
记住……-最小的事情，不要忘记。-我不会忘记的。
And remember... - the smallest thing, don't forget. - I won't forget.
亲爱的艾米丽。
Dear Emily.
-青蛙，贾德森。-是的，先生。
- Frog please Judson. - Yes sir.
-您的青蛙先生-请把他放在那儿
- Your frog sir. - Oh, put him down there please.
现在，如果我们把原电池的一端与神经接触…另一个与肌肉接触，引起肌肉收缩。
Now, if we place one terminal of the galvanic battery in contact with the nerve... and the other in contact with muscle, we cause a contraction of the muscle.
在那里。你看到了什么?
There. You see?
现在，如果你能像控制人类大脑的反应一样容易…我对你的工作还是有点信心的。
Now, if you could control the responses of the human mind as easily as you control... the muscles of a frog I might've some faith in your work.
总有一天，如果我们继续我们的研究，我们也许能做到。
Someday, we may be able to if we continue our research.
-如果你继续你的工作…-不不不不
- And if you were to continue your work... - No, no, no, no.
你知道吗，我觉得你应该努力让自己从恐惧中解脱出来。
You know, I think you should make an effort to take your mind off your fears.
你应该离开这个地方。带艾米丽去威尼斯。
You should get away from this place. Take Emily to Venice.
当你回来的时候，你的大部分问题都会消失。
Then when you return most of your problem would've disappeared.
也许你是对的，我会考虑的。
Perhaps you're right, I'll think about it.
不要想，要去做。
Don't think about it, do it.
好吧，我先把你留给你的小朋友们。
I may, meanwhile I'll leave you to your little friends.
-你想继续吗，先生?-是的，贾德森。
- Do you wish to continue sir, eh? - Oh yes Judson.
你和迈尔斯是对的。我偶尔也得出去走走。
You and Miles were right. I do have to get outside occasionally.
我告诉过你，我们只需要彼此。
I told you, all we need is each other.
-我们不需要别的东西就能快乐。-这是真的，这是真的
- We need nothing else to be happy. - How true, how true that really is.
这是什么?
What is it?
听。
Listen.
-怎么了，盖伊?-吹口哨。
- What's the matter Guy? - That whistling.
-我什么都没听到。-听着，我告诉你
- I don't hear anything. - Listen, I tell you.
盖，盖，别跑。
Guy, Guy don't run away.
的家伙。
Guy.
盖伊，盖伊，盖伊，盖伊。
Guy, Guy, Guy, Guy.
-亲爱的，怎么了?-我看到了。
- Darling, darling, what's wrong? - I saw them.
你看见谁了?
You saw whom?
那两个肮脏的盗墓贼，他们是来找我的，问问爱米丽，她也看见了。
Those two filthy grave robbers, they were coming for me, ask Emily she saw them too.
-没有，我谁也没看见。-但你一定看到了，他们从我们身边经过。
- No, I saw no one. - But you must've, they passed right by us.
-你肯定听到了。-伙计，你太激动了。
- Surely you heard them. - Guy, you're overwrought.
请给我。
I, please.
他们是冲着我来的。
They were coming for me.
-没人质疑你的话，盖伊。-别逗我，我没生气。
- No one questions your word Guy. - Don't humor me, I'm not mad.
我看到他们就像看到你一样清楚。
I saw them as clearly as I'm seeing you.
亲爱的，我们回家吧，你可以休息一下……那你就可以说话了。
Darling, let's go back to the house and you can rest and... well, then you can talk.
来吧。
Come on.
你没看到他们?
You didn't see them?
没有，当时又黑又多雾。
No, it was dark and foggy.
我一会儿就去楼下找你。我只是想多休息一会儿。
I'll join you downstairs in a little while. I just want to rest some more.
好的，亲爱的，我们都在等你。
All right darling, we'll all be waiting for you..
-他怎么样了艾米丽?-我觉得他好多了。
- How is he Emily? - Well, he's better I think.
-他在休息。——好。
- He's resting. - Good.
你觉得他看到了什么，迈尔斯?
What you think he saw Miles?
跟他说的一模一样，两个盗墓贼。
Exactly what he said, the two grave robbers.
-我怎么没看出来?-因为他们不是真的。
- But why didn't I see? - Because they weren't real.
你是说，它们是超自然的东西?
You mean, they were something supernatural?
我不否认超自然现象的可能性。
I don't deny the possibility of the supernatural.
然而，我相信还有更合理的解释。
However, I do believe that there's a more logical explanation.
你看，艾米丽，人类的思想，是一种了不起的工具。
You see Emily, the human mind, it's a remarkable instrument.
它可以从无到有创造出一些东西，这可能就是发生的事情。
It can create something out of nothing and that's probably what happened.
你想说的是…-他疯了。-不，没有那种事。
Well, what you're trying to say is that... - Guy is mad. - No, nothing of the sort.
他有心理障碍，这是有区别的。
He's disturbed and there's a difference.
-如果他父亲过早被埋葬…-他没有。
- If his father was prematurely interred... - He wasn't.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know?
我知道，因为我去了地下室，亲眼看到了。
I know because I went to the crypt and saw for myself.
我父亲安息了。
My father rests in peace.
是风。
It's the wind.
——人。-他在那儿。
- Guy. - He's there.
-那里没人。-但你一定见过他。
- There's nobody there. - But you must've seen him.
我只看到了你，盖伊。
I saw only you Guy.
迈尔斯，我们该怎么办?自从那晚在荒原上，他就…我只是认不出他了。
Miles, what we going to do? Ever since that night on the moors, he's been... Well, I just don't recognize him anymore.
-你邀请他和你一起走了吗?-我怎么能?
- Have you asked him to go away with you? - How can I?
他不肯从那个可怕的地方出来，也不让我进去。
He won't come out of that terrible place and won't let me in.
他只想坐着沉思。
All he wants to do is just sit and brood.
-迈尔斯，你得做点什么。-艾米丽，我已经尽力了。
- Miles, you got to do something. - Emily, I'm afraid I've done all I can.
总有一天，治疗心灵会成为一门科学……他们将能够处理这样的问题。
Someday, treatment of the mind will be a science... and they'll be able to cope with such problems.
但在现阶段，艾米丽有一件事我们还没试过。
But at this present stage, Emily there is one thing we haven't tried.
那就告诉我该怎么做。
Well, just tell me what to do.
家伙?伙计，让我进去。
Guy? Guy, let me in.
这真是个惊喜。
Well, this is quite a surprise.
除了打扰我的工作，你这次来还有什么目的吗?
Is there any purpose to this visit apart that is, from interrupting my work?
是的。
Yes.
-我以为你已经放弃画画了。-这只是一幅肖像画。
- Thought you'd given up painting. - It's merely portraiture.
-假设我进入了一个新的时期。-我可以看看吗?
- Let us say I'm entering a new period. - May I see it?
-我想你会不高兴的。-当然应该由我来决定。
- I don't think you'd find it very pleasing. - Surely I should be the one to decide that.
好吧，别说我没警告过你。
Very well, don't say I didn't warn you.
我虔诚地把它称为一种圆满的愿望。
I call it some consummations devoutly to be wished.
-为什么?——思考。
- But why? - Think.
你在这里看到的这些可怕的折磨，刑架和木桩……这整个可怕的目录难道不是真的值得虔诚地祈祷吗……
All these dreadful tortures you see depicted here, the rack and the stake... the whole ghastly catalog are they not indeed devoutly to be wished...
你宁愿接受最可怕的命运吗?
preferred to that fate which is the most terrible of all?
这种命运已经发生了，盖伊。
That fate has already come to pass Guy.
-你在说什么?-关于你。
- What are you talking about? - About you.
你不怕被活埋，因为你已经被活埋了。
You don't fear burial alive because you are already buried alive.
你到底在怕什么?被锁在坟墓里?
What is it you're afraid of? Being locked in a tomb?
你已经被锁在坟墓里好几个月了。
Why, you've been locked in a tomb for months.
这个坟墓。
This tomb.
我做过你的寡妇，我不喜欢做你的寡妇，盖伊。
And I've been your widow and I don't like being your widow Guy.
更重要的是，我不会待太久。
And what's more, I'm not going to be much longer.
——艾米丽。-不盖伊，我是来给你个选择的
- Emily. - No Guy, I'm here to give you a choice.
你可以选择这个，这个活死人，或者你可以选择我…但你不能两者兼得。
You can have this, this living death or you can have me... but you can't have both.
请艾米丽。
Emily, please.
我爱你，盖伊，我非常爱你，我想照顾你……但只要你在这里，我就不能。没人能做到。
I love you Guy, I love you very much and I want to take care of you... but as long as you're here, I can't. No one can.
我知道，但是……-我好害怕。-哦，你不必做我亲爱的。
I realize that, but... - I'm so afraid. - Oh, you needn't be my darling.
我向你保证。看着我。
I promise you. Look at me.
我向你保证，无论发生什么…我绝不会让他们把你贬到那种地步……那个可怕的地窖。
I promise you that no matter what happens... I'll never let them take you down to that... that horrible crypt.
-相信我能照顾好你。-我相信你，艾米丽，但不是那样
- Trust me to take care of you. - I do trust you Emily, but it isn't that.
盖伊，如果你选择了我…那你必须摧毁这个邪恶的金库。
Guy, if you do choose me... then you must destroy this evil vault.
把它从地球上抹去，永远从你的脑海里抹去。
Wipe it off the face of the earth and out of your mind forever.
如果你不……
If you don't...
那我就再也见不到你了。
then I shall never see you again.
好吧，到底是哪一个呢?
Well, which is it to be?
你自己去死还是和我一起生?
Death by yourself or life with me?
艾米丽。
Emily.
请原谅我，亲爱的。
Please forgive me darling.
我不想失去你，我就是不能，无论如何都不能。
I wouldn't lose you, I just couldn't, not for anything.
哦，盖伊，我爱你。
Oh Guy, I love you.
伙计，那需要很大的勇气。
Guy, that took great courage.
不…我又一次被恐惧所驱使，害怕失去比生命更有价值的东西。
No... once again I was motivated by fear, fear of losing something more valuable than my life.
-你永远不会后悔的。-上帝保佑你是对的。
- You'll never regret it. - I pray God you're right.
我想感谢你们二位邀请我参加婚礼。
I want to thank you both for asking me to the ceremony.
我猜你现在要去度蜜月了，是吧?
I suppose that now you'll be having that honeymoon, eh?
是的，但首先周五晚上会有一个小型聚会。
Yes, but first there will be a small party Friday night.
你会和我们在一起的，迈尔斯，对吧?
You will be with us, Miles, won't you?
如果你父亲不打算让我继续在医院工作的话。
If your father doesn't take it into his mind to keep me working at the hospital.
他不会的，因为我们会邀请你们两个。
Oh, he won't, because we shall invite both of you.
那么，当然，在这种情况下。
Well then, of course, in that case.
-凯瑟琳夫人?-老爷?
- Lady Catherine? - Mi lord?
谢谢你，贾德森。
Thank you Judson.
我的朋友们，为了生活。
My friends, to life.
-高尔特医生，要来支雪茄吗?-哦，谢谢。是的。
- Dr. Gault, would you like a cigar? - Oh, thank you. Yes.
-加入我们，迈尔斯?-等一下。
- Join us Miles? - In just a moment.
真了不起，凯瑟琳夫人，但他看起来很健康，你不觉得吗?
It's extraordinary Lady Catherine, but he looks the picture of health, don't you agree?
外表有时会欺骗亚彻博士。
Looks can be deceiving Dr. Archer.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
请允许我对您的康复表示祝贺。
Well, permit me to offer my congratulations on your lordship's recovery.
我觉得你应该把它们交给艾米丽和迈尔斯，他们是有责任的。
I think you should offer them to Emily and to Miles, they are responsible.
-好吧，神父，你玩得开心吗?-我从来都不开心。
- Well Father, are you enjoying yourself? - I never enjoy myself.
我只是经历了或多或少的无聊，仅此而已。
I merely experience greater and lesser degrees of tedium, that's all.
只是那只猫，亲爱的。
It's just the cat darling.
是的，我知道，但是她为什么要那样哭呢?
Yes, I know but why should she cry like that?
饿了吧，我想。
Hungry, I expect.
-她在哪儿?-我不知道。
- Where is she? - I don't know.
-听起来好像是从那边传来的。-可怜的小东西一定是被卡住了。
- Sounds as if it's coming from over there. - Poor little thing must be stuck.
等一下。
Wait a moment.
在这里。
Is down here.
看这里。
Look at that, down here.
在这里，在那里。
Down here, there it is.
好了，老伙计，我们一会儿就把你弄出来。
All right old girl, we'll have you out in a moment.
-她是怎么到后面去的?-一定是爬过去的
- How ever could she got behind there? - Must've crawled through.
把这可怜的小东西给我吧。
Let me have the poor wee thing.
发生了什么事啊。
What a thing to happen.
-看到了吗?毕竟没有造成伤害。-她没事的。
- There you see? No harm done after all. - There, she's all right.
伙计，你还好吧?
Guy, you all right?
-如果我们没听到她的声音呢?-我们听到了。
- What if we hadn't heard her? - We did hear her.
你还没有把这些想法从脑海中抹去，是吗?
You haven't put these thoughts out of your mind after all, have you?
哦，当然了。
Oh, of course he has.
-这只是一种…-你没有吧?
- This is just a sort of... - You haven't, have you?
伙计，你别再想这些了。
Guy, you got to put it out of your mind.
我试过了，我什么都试过了。
I've tried, I've tried everything.
不是万能的。
Not everything.
盖伊，你对麻痹症的恐惧是…基于你认为你父亲被过早埋葬的信念，对吗?
Guy, your fear of catalepsy is... based on your belief that your father was prematurely buried, isn't that correct?
-我听到了，我听到了他的声音。-你觉得你听到了。
- I heard him, I heard his voice. - You think you heard it.
-我听到了他的声音。-那就证明给我看
- I heard his voice. - All right, then prove it.
-什么意思?-证明给我看
- What do you mean? - Just that, prove it.
带我去地下室，让我看看他的尸体。
Take me down to the crypt and show me his body.
-不行。-因为你知道那不是真的。
- I can't. - Because you know it isn't true.
——没有。——是的。
- No. - Yes.
不然你为什么会逃避呢?
Why else you think you've avoided it?
因为你害怕，害怕这种恐惧只不过是你大脑的一个把戏。
Because you're afraid, afraid that this fear is nothing more than a trick of your mind.
我愿意付出任何代价去查明那是不是真的。
I'd give anything to find out if that were true.
好吧，带我下楼。
All right then, take me downstairs.
好吧，我会的。
All right, I will.
-不，盖伊，你不觉得你应该休息一下吗?——艾米丽……迈尔斯说得对，我已经拖得够久了。
- No Guy, don't you think you should rest? - Emily... Miles is right, I've put this off long enough.
-地窖的钥匙不见了-谁能拿到这些?
- The key to the crypt, it's gone. - Who has access to these?
-只有我自己。-但你一直锁着?
- No one but myself. - But you keep it locked?
没有,但是……盖伊，你是下来拿钥匙的吗?
No, but... Guy, did you come down here and take the key?
我不这么想。
I don't think so.
有人可能做了那样的事却不记得吗?
Is it possible for someone to do a thing like that and not remember it?
有可能，你承认最近做了很多你不记得的事情。
It's possible, you admit to doing many things lately that you don't remember.
这不重要，把它打开。
Well, it's unimportant, break it open.
跟我来。
Follow me.
-是哪一个?-在那边。
- Which one is it? - Over there.
-不行。-你最喜欢。
- I can't. - You most.
这是你唯一的机会，如果你现在失败了你将永远被困扰。
Is your only chance, if you fail now you'll be haunted forever.
凯特，给我一面镜子。
Kate, bring me a mirror.
你在浪费时间，他已经死了。
You're wasting your time, he's dead.
不。不，他不可能。不能。
No. No, he can't be. Can't be.
他完成了。
He's finished.
-心脏病发作。-哦，不。
- Heart attack. - Oh, no.
-你确定吗，高尔特医生?-当然了。
- Are you sure, Dr. Gault? - Of course I am.
没有，没有生命迹象但为了确保万无一失我们应该再做一次测试。
No, there's no sign of life but to be absolutely sure we should make one more test.
愚蠢的阿切尔，那人死了。
Foolishness Archer, the man is dead.
贾德森，帮我拿原电池。
Judson, help me with the galvanic battery.
不，别这样，听我说。我还活着，你听不见我吗?
No, don't do this, listen to me. I'm alive, can't you hear me?
我还活着，还活着。
I'm alive, I'm alive.
凯特，你和艾米丽最好离开房间。
Kate, you and Emily better leave the room.
迈尔斯，迈尔斯，看在上帝的份上。
Oh, Miles, Miles, in the name of heaven.
好吗?他死了还是没死?
Well? Is he dead or isn't he?
-是的。-不，我没死，我还活着。
- He is. - No, I'm not dead, I', alive.
贾德森，帮我拿电池。
Judson, help me with the battery.
我们还是把他带回墓穴吧。
We may as well take him back to the crypt.
不，我答应过他无论发生什么我都不会让他们把他带到地下墓穴。
No, I promised him no matter what happens I'd never let them take him down to the crypt.
艾米丽的废话。好吧，这是你的决定。
Nonsense Emily. Oh well, is your decision.
女人所生的男人寿命很短，而且充满苦难。
Man that is born of woman hath but a short time to live and is full of misery.
他上来，像花一样被砍倒。
He cometh up and is cut down like a flower.
他像影子一样逃窜，永不停留。
He fleeth as it were a shadow and never continueth in one stay.
在生命中，我们在死亡中。
In the midst of life, we are in death.
除了你，我们还能向谁寻求帮助呢?谁因我们的罪有正当的不喜悦呢?
Of whom may we seek for succor but of thee dear Lord... who for our sins art justly displeased?
然而，万能的上帝啊。
Yet, oh Lord God most mighty.
哦，神圣而仁慈的救世主，不要让我们陷入永恒死亡的痛苦之中。
Oh holy and most merciful savior deliver us not into the bitter pain of eternal death.
主啊，你知道我们心中的秘密。
Thou knowest Lord the secrets of our hearts.
不要对你的祈祷闭上仁慈的耳朵，宽恕我们吧，最强大的上帝。
Shut not thy merciful ears to thy prayers but spare us, God most mighty.
啊，最仁慈的救主，你最配得上永恒的审判者……在我们最后的时刻，不要让任何死亡的痛苦从你身上降临。
O most merciful savior, thou most worthy judge eternal... suffer us not at our last hour for any pains of death to fall from thee.
不要让我们受苦。
Suffer us not.
死亡的痛苦。哦，求你了，帮帮我。谁来帮帮我。
Pains of death. Oh please, help me. Someone, help me.
帮助我。
Help me.
阿们。
Amen.
你现在可以说再见了。
You may say farewell now.
再见，亲爱的。
Good-bye my darling.
艾米丽，艾米丽，回来。回来了。
Emily, Emily come back. Come back.
他们会看到我，他们会看着我的眼睛。
They'll see me, they'll look at my eyes.
他们不会带我去地下室的。但是，他们要带我去哪里?
They're not taking me to the crypt. But, where are they taking me?
在哪里?在哪里?为什么我动不了?
Where? Where? Why can't I move?
天啊，为什么我动不了?
Oh God, why can't I move?
仁慈的上帝啊，我们将盖伊·卡雷尔的灵魂…吉迪恩和阿加莎·卡雷尔的儿子，愿你永远照顾他。
O merciful God, we consign the soul of Guy Carrell... son of Gideon and Agatha Carrell to thine eternal care.
阿们。
Amen.
看着我，有人，看着我。
Look at me, someone, look at me.
看在上帝的份上，求你了。你不能活埋我。
Oh, for God's sake, please. You can't bury me alive.
难道你看不见我还活着吗?
Can't you see I'm alive?
天啊，为什么我动不了?为什么我动不了?
God, why can't I move? Why can't I move?
不,不。帮助我。
No, no. Help me.
谁来帮帮我。我还活着，你听不见我吗?你看不见我的眼睛吗?
Someone help me. I'm alive, can't you hear me? Can't you see my eyes?
我还活着，活着，艾莉…
I'm alive, alive, Ali...
我想你会在读完遗嘱后离开。
You'll be leaving I suppose, after the reading of the will.
你为什么这么说?
Why should you say that?
没有理由。
No reason.
我只是想，在这种情况下，你可能会觉得这房子很令人不安。
I merely thought that under the circumstances you might find this house rather disturbing.
我是说对你的良心。
To your conscience, I mean.
凯特，你是在暗示艾米丽对盖伊的死有任何责任吗?
Kate, are you implying that Emily is in any way responsible for Guy's death?
没有人对此负责。
No one is responsible.
他死于休克引起的心脏病发作，你不明白吗?
He died of a heart attack induced by shock, don't you understand?
是的。我明白了。
Yes. I understand.
事实是他自己带来了震惊。
The fact is he brought on the shock himself.
地窖里的那一幕还有其他所有的事，都是精心策划的，你不明白吗?
The episode in the crypt and all the others, they were planned, contrived, don't you see?
——计划?由谁?-盖伊自己写的。
- Planned? By whom? - By Guy himself.
他想以一种奇怪的方式死去。
In a strange way he wanted to die.
别再谈论他了。别再谈论他了。
Stop talking about him. Stop talking about him.
-太过分了，斯威尼先生。鼹鼠先生是什么?
- That's a bit much Mr. Sweeney. - What is Mr. Mole?
那位老先生派我们来挖这个的。
The old gentleman sending us out here to dig up this one.
-我是说他的女婿-尸体都差不多啊。
- I mean, his own son in law. - Well, one stiff's pretty much like another.
哦，我们找到线索了。那该死的撬棍在哪?
Oh, we've struck wood. Now, where's the bloody crowbar?
我记得我把它落在上面了。
I believe I left it up on top.
鼹鼠先生，你能帮我把它拿下来吗?
Well Mr. Mole, would you do me the kindness to fetch it down?
好的，斯威尼先生。
Yes, I will Mr. Sweeney.
-我找到了，斯威尼先生——嗯?不。
- I found it Mr. Sweeney. - Eh? No.
不，我从没对你做过什么。请,请。
No, I never did nothing to you. Please, please.
我从没对你做过什么，求你了。
I've never done nothing to you, please.
斯威尼，你这个喋喋不休的白痴。什么你…我让你带他去我的住处。
Sweeney, you blithering idiot. What you... I told you to take him to my quarters.
好吧，还是现在就去看看他吧。
Oh well, may as well have a look at him now, yes.
很讽刺，你不觉得吗?非常合适。
Ironic, don't you think? And rather fitting really.
盖伊·卡雷尔一生对医学毫无贡献。
In life, Guy Carrell contributed nothing to medical science.
死后，他将为之尽忠职守。
In death, he shall serve it admirably.
斯威尼?
Sweeney?
不，你死了，不……
No, you're dead, no...
艾米丽，你什么毛病都没有。
Emily, there's nothing whatever wrong with you.
嗯，也许不是身体上的。
Well, not physically perhaps.
-那你为什么派贾德森来找我?-我害怕一个人呆着。
- Then why did you send Judson for me? - Well, I was afraid to be alone.
哦，我，我能理解。
Oh, I, I can understand that.
-也许你不该来这里。-哦，迈尔斯，你不明白吗?
- Perhaps you shouldn't be here. - Oh Miles, don't you see...
请过来坐下。好吗?
Please come and sit down. Please?
现在，就一会儿，然后你必须去睡觉。
Now, just for a moment and then you must go to sleep.
迈尔斯，你一定知道，或者至少你一定感觉到……我今天一直很担心……我需要某件事或某个人给我安慰。
Miles, you must know or at least you must sense that... I've been very worried today... that I'm in need of something or someone to give me solace.
你和我曾经很亲密，迈尔斯。
You and I were very close once Miles.
你还记得吧?
You remember that, don't you?
我记得有个医学院学生穷得像教堂里的老鼠…一个想成为伟大女士的女孩。
I can remember a medical student who was poor as a church mouse... and a girl who wanted to be a great lady.
我很愚蠢。
I was very foolish.
-哦，迈尔斯，也许我们现在还不算太晚。-但是艾米丽…
- Oh Miles, maybe it's not too late for us. - But Emily...
我犯了一个错误。
I made a mistake.
这有那么错吗?
Is that so very wrong?
进来。
Come in.
-亚彻博士?-怎么了，贾德森?
- Dr. Archer? - What is it Judson?
对不起，女士。
It's, excuse me milady.
如果你愿意的话，我想让你看看这个。
It's something I'd like you to see sir, if you would.
-医疗问题?——是的。
- A medical matter? - Yes.
那高尔特医生肯定能搞定。
Well, then certainly Dr. Gault could take care of it.
我想高尔特医生会希望你尽快过来的，先生。
I think Dr. Gault would want you to come as quickly as possible sir.
也许你最好去迈尔斯。
Perhaps you had better go Miles.
来吧，贾德森。
Now come along Judson.
贾德森，你怎么这么奇怪?
Judson why are you behaving so oddly?
我听到实验室有声音，先生，就在刚才，然后……——是吗?-你自己看吧，先生。
I heard a sound from the laboratory sir, just a bit ago and... - Yes? - See for yourself sir.
那是谁?英里?
Who's that? Miles?
不欢迎?
No welcome?
没有快乐吗?
No rejoicing?
没有吻吗?
No kiss?
-电致死亡。-亚彻博士…
- Killed by electrical force. - Dr. Archer...
这是《理发师陶德》。
That's Sweeney.
艾米丽。
Emily.
艾米丽?
Emily?
的家伙。
Guy.
现在…伙计，你得听我说。
Now... Guy, you got to listen to me.
什么?更多的谎言吗?更多的欺骗吗?更多的背叛?
To what? More lies? More deceit? More treachery?
-不，不，不是这样的-哦，但它是。
- No, no, that's not true. - Oh, but it is.
你很聪明，艾米丽，很聪明。
You were very clever Emily, very clever.
-在某种程度上，我很抱歉破坏了你的计划。-我没有安排，是凯特。
- In a way I'm sorry to spoil your plans. - Oh, I had no plans, it was Kate.
你不会杀了我吧，盖伊?
You wouldn't kill me, would you Guy?
不，亲爱的，一点也不，就像你没有杀我一样。
No darling, not at all, just as you didn't kill me.
你不会让谋杀弄脏你漂亮的手的。
You wouldn't soil your pretty hands with murder.
不，你只是袖手旁观，让他们把我活埋。
No, you just stood aside and let them bury me alive.
不，伙计，不。
No Guy, no.
所以，我不会杀你。
And so, I shall not kill you.
我将把这可悲的任务留给大地和黑暗……还有你内心的恐惧。
That sorry task I shall leave to the earth and the darkness... and the terrified pounding of your own heart.
盖伊，不，不是那个。
Guy no, not that.
是的，我美丽的，背信弃义的，背信弃义的爱人。
Yes, my beautiful, my perfidious, my treacherous love, that.
没有人。
No Guy.
的家伙。
Guy.
待在原地别动，迈尔斯。我无意伤害你。
Stay precisely where you are Miles. I've no desire to harm you.
-你做了什么，盖伊?-偿还了一笔长期债务。
- What have you done Guy? - Paid a debt of long standing.
不，这与你无关。今晚早些时候我发现的。
No, this has nothing to do with you. I found that out earlier this evening.
-天哪，盖伊。-是的，以上帝的名义。
- In heaven's name Guy. - Yes, in heaven's name.
把铲子给我。
Give me that shovel.
她死了。
She's dead.
-谢天谢地。-凯特，你在说什么?
- Thank God. - Kate, what are you saying?
你这么瞎吗?你看不出来吗?
Are you so blind? Can't you see?
-那是地窖的钥匙。-她没时间换新的
- That's the key to the crypt. - She had no time to replace it.
-我真不敢相信艾米丽-是的，艾米丽
- I can't believe it, not Emily. - Yes, Emily.
可爱，美丽，温柔的艾米丽。
Sweet, beautiful, gentle Emily.
一旦你告诉她利用盖伊的恐惧来杀死他是多么容易，她就去工作了。
Once you told her how easy it would be to use Guy's fear to kill him, she went to work.
首先，雇佣盗墓贼来折磨他……墙里的猫……最后是亵渎我们父亲的坟墓。
First, the hiring of the grave robbers to torment him... the cat in the wall... and finally the desecration of our father's tomb.
哦的家伙…我知道她在做什么，我想告诉你，但你不会相信我的。
Oh Guy... I knew what she was doing and I wanted to tell you but you wouldn't have believed me.
我不得不等待证据。你看得出来，不是吗?
I had to wait for proof. You can see that, can't you?
但我等得太久了。我来晚了。
But I waited too long. I was too late.
太晚了
Too late.